hi my name is Joe Brewer and I'm a
change strategist and today I want to
review another book for you that I
recently read this one going viral biker
n dejan and Jeff Hemsley at the
University of Washington and this book
is all about how media events can go
viral or and said another way how
information can spread across social
networks and go from a very small number
of people being exposed to a piece of
information to very quickly a very large
number of people sharing and then being
exposed to that information this book is
really wonderful for anyone who is
interested in understanding how the
changing media landscape say from mass
production to peer-to-peer
communications has dramatically altered
the way that or shared social reality is
constructed and the way that information
can become normalized in our society by
becoming ubiquitous so you've probably
heard about things like the Pharaoh
Williams song happy that went viral
globally it has now been viewed hundreds
of millions of times on YouTube or
earlier two years ago when Gangnam style
dance came out of Seoul South Korea and
quickly achieved greater than 1 billion
views on YouTube to understand how those
kinds of viral events are indicators of
what is relevant and important for
people in their lives and also as a way
of understanding how communication
happens in our peer-to-peer world this
book is really really excellent because
what it does is it goes through a number
of key intellectual or analytic points
about how to understand what social
networks are how the the mathematics of
connections between people so you know
some people have more connections others
have less and there are different
arrangements for how those connections
work can influence the kind of
information that spreads and how it
spreads also there are factors around
psychology of the content and also the
zeitgeist or that the concerns
sentiments aspirations that are
widespread in relevant at a particular
in time and so this book goes into the
different analytic techniques the
different social theory or social
science kinds of interpretations of
different events and it also explores
the very important notion that what
becomes viral is a great measure of what
is important and so now that we have so
much data about what is being spread on
the internet because it's digital
information we're able to track cultural
change and see what's important day to
day month to month and year to year and
so there's a call for creating archives
of viral content to understand what is
important and relevant to people at
particular points in time so this is a
book that I recommend for anyone who
wants to understand the dynamics of
social change in today's rapidly
changing world if they want to know how
to spread messages or run successful
campaigns to try to influence public
discourse and of course as researchers
to understand the inherent dynamics of
sharing behavior and the politics and
power arrangements of that sharing
behavior in culture as it is changing in
time so that's the book going viral I
highly recommend it as a great companion
to any attempt to understand changing
patterns and culture so that's it I hope
you enjoy and um let me know what you
think